Guide to the Collection of Type Specimens
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Type Specimens
1826-1995
AOB 55
Yale University Arts Library
13.5
(12 boxes)
The collection comprises ephemeral type specimens in a variety of formats, including pamphlets, single sheets, and broadsides.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials acquired primarily by purchase.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises ephemeral type specimens: pamphlets, single sheets, and broadsides. Series I contains materials that document a single font or font family. Series II contains materials that document more than one font; they are listed by the manufacturer or distributor. Series III is a clipping file with information on typographers. Series IV contains broadsides, divided into four subseries: Typeface; Manufacturer; Typographer; and Calligraphy and Lettering.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Typeface. II. Manufacturer. III. Typographer. IV. Broadsides. V. Miscellaneous.
Entries are arranged alphabetically within each category.
Computer fonts -- Specimens; Type and type-founding -- Digital techniques; Type and type-founding -- Specimens; Type specimens (documents)
- Typeface, Series I
  Arrangement
  Typeface specimens in this series are ordered alphabetically by the name of the font or font family. The typeface manufacturer or designer, or both, are listed following the font name. A date indicates the date of publication for the typeface specimen.
  - Abrams Venetian, George Abrams Alphabets Inc., George Abrams, Poul Kristensen, 1987; 1 (Box 1)
  - Akzidenz Grotesk, The Composing Room Inc., 1950; 2 (Box 1)
  - Akzidenz Grotesk, 1978; 3 (Box 1)
  - Albertus, Westcott & Thompson Inc., Berthold Wolpe, 1950; 1 (Box 1)
  - Amanda, Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Amazone, Typefoundry Amsterdam, s, 1959; 4 (Box 1)
  - American Typewriter, International Typeface Corp., 1975; 2 (Box 1)
  - Americana, American Type Founders, Richard Isbell, 1976; 1 (Box 1)
  - Americana, Eltra Corp., 1976; 1 (Box 1)
  - Antiqua Firmin Didot, Ludwig & Mayer, 1930; 1 (Box 1)
  - Antique, Fonderie Olive, undated; 1 (Box 9)
  - Arena, H. Berthold AG, 1957; 1 (Box 1)
  - Ariston, Continental Typefounders, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Ariston Medium, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Berthold Typefoundry, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Arrighi, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Aster, Simoncini, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Astoria, Bauer Alphabets, undated; 3 (Box 1)
  - Astree, Continental Typefounders Association Inc., 1923; 1 (Box 1)
  - Augustea, Amsterdam Continental, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Aurora, Amsterdam Continental, C.E. Weber Type Foundry, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Avant Garde, Mergenthaler, Linotype, Stempel, Haas, 1978; 3 (Box 1)
  - Avant Garde Gothic, Lubalin, Burns & Company, 1970; 1 (Box 1)
  - Avant Garde Gothic and Condensed, International Typeface Corporation, 1977; 6 (Box 1)
  - Balzac, D. Stempel AG, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - Barbou, Monotype Corp., undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Barcelona, International Typeface Corporation, 1981; 1 (Box 1)
  - Baskerville, Mergenthaler Linotype Company, John Baskerville, 1930; 1 (Box 1)
  - Baskerville/New Baskerville, TypoGrpahics Communications, Inc. (distributor), Mergenthaler, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Baskerville, The Stinehour Press (distributor), Mergenthaler Linoterm, 1980; 1 (Box 1)
  - Baskerville, The Stinehour Press (distributor), Monotype & American Type Founders, 1980; 1 (Box 1)
  - Baskerville, The Composing Room Inc., American Type Founders & Monotype, 1940; 3 (Box 1)
  - Baskerville, Stephenson Blake (distributor), Fry & Steele, 1922; 3 (Box 9)
  - New Baskerville, International Typeface Corp., 1982; 3 (Box 1)
  - Bauer, Bauer Type Foundry, Inc., undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bauer Topic, Bauer Alphabets Inc., Paul Renner, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bauhaus, International Typeface Corporation, 1976; 2 (Box 1)
  - Bell, American Book Stratford Press, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bell Types, Cosmos Press, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bell Types, Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bembo, Monotype Corp., undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bembo, Stinehour Press (distributor), Mergenthaler Linoterm, 1980; 1 (Box 1)
  - Benedictine, Mergenthaler Linotype, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Benguiat, International Typeface Corp., 1977; 5 (Box 1)
  - Benguiat Condensed, International Typeface Corp., Ed Benguiat, 1979; 4 (Box 1)
  - Benguiat Gothic, International Typeface Corp., Ed Benguiat, 1979; 3 (Box 1)
  - Berkley Old Style, International Typeface Corp., 1983; 3 (Box 1)
  - Bernhard Modern, American Type Founders, Lucian Bernhard, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bernhard Cursive, Bauer Alphabets Inc., Lucian Bernhard, 1950; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bernhard Gothic, American Type Founders, Lucian Bernhard, 1929-1931; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bernhard Tango, American Type Founders, Lucian Bernhard, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Beton, Bauer Alphabets Inc., 1930; 1 (Box 1)
  - Beton, Intertype, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bifur, Continental Typefounders, A.M. Cassandre, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bodoni, Bauer Alphabets Inc./Bauer Typefoundry, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bodoni, Eastern Corporation, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bodoni, Lanston Monotype Machine Co., 1930; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bodoni, Linotype, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bodoni Bold, John C. Meyer & Son, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bologna, Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bookface, Intertype, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bookman, International Typeface Corporation, 1976; 3 (Box 1)
  - Boul Mich, Barnhart Brothers & Spindler, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Britannic, American Wood Type Mfg. Co. (distributor), Stephenson Blake, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - Brush, American Type Founders, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bulmer, American Type Founders, 1928; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bulmer, Intertype, 1958; 1 (Box 1)
  - Bulmer, Lanston Monotype Machine Co., undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Caflisch, Adobe, 1993; 1 (Box 1)
  - Cairo, Intertype, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Caledonia, Merganthaler Linotype, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Cantate, Bauer Alphabets Inc., undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Card Mercantile, American Type Founders, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Cartoon, Bauer Type Foundry/Bauer Alphabets, Howard Trafton, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Caslon, Adobe Systems Inc., Carol Twombly, 1990; 2 (Box 1)
  - Caslon, American Type Founders, 1923; 1 (Box 1)
  - Caslon, International Typeface Corporation, 1983; 3 (Box 1)
  - Caslon, Monotype Corp., 1966; 1 (Box 1)
  - Caslon, Stephenson Blake, 1930; 1 (Box 1)
  - Caslon, The Stinehour Press (distributor), Monotype, 1983; 1 (Box 1)
  - Casual Gothic, Lettering Inc., undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Casual Latin, Lettering Inc., undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Centaur, Continental Typefounders Association, Bruce Rogers, 1935; 1 (Box 1)
  - Century, Barnes Printing Co. (distributor), Linotype, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Century, International Typeface Corp., 1980; 4 (Box 1)
  - Century Expanded, American Type Founders, Linn Boyd Benton, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Century Modern, Lettering Inc., not dated, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Century Nova, American Type Founders, Charles E. Hughes, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Century Nova, John C. Meyer & Son, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Century Schoolbook, Monotype Corporation Ltd./Lanston Monotype Machine Co., undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Charlemagne, Adobe, 1989; 3 (Box 1)
  - Cheltenham, International Typeface Corporation, Tony Stan, 1978; 4 (Box 1)
  - City, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Berthold Typefoundry, 1978; 3 (Box 1)
  - Clarendon, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Haas Typefoundry, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Clarendon, The Composing Room Inc., 1964; 3 (Box 1)
  - Classic, Tudor Typographers (distributor), Bauer Alphabets, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Clearface, International Typeface Corporation, Morris Fuller Beton/Victor Caruso, 1979; 4 (Box 1)
  - Cochin Series, Mergenthaler, 1977, 1 (Box 1)
  - Columbia, Amsterdam Continental, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - Columbia, Typefoundry Amsterdam, Walter H. McKay, 1952; 1 (Box 1)
  - Compact Grotesque, Lettering Inc., undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Condensed Gothic No. 13, Intertype, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Consort, Lettering Inc., undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Consort Series, American Wood Type Manufacturing Co. (distributor), Stephenson Blake, undated; 3 (Box 2)
  - Contact, American Type Founders, Frank Riley, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Cooper Black Italic, American Type Founders, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Cornell, Intertype, George F. Trenholm, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Corona, Mergenthaler Linotype, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Coronet, Ludlow Typograph Co., undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Corvinus, Bauer Type Foundry, Imre Reiner, 1935; 1 (Box 2)
  - Craw Clarendon, American Type Founders, Freeman Craw, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Craw Clarendon, Lanston Monotype Company, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Craw Modern, American Type Founders, Freeman Craw, undated; 3 (Box 2)
  - Cushing, International Typeface Corporation, 1982; 2 (Box 2)
  - De Roos, Amsterdam Continental, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Della Robbia Series, Mergenthaler, 1977; 2 (Box 2)
  - Delphin/Delphin II, C.E. Weber, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - De Vinne Series, Mergenthaler Linotype Co., 1928; 1 (Box 2)
  - Didot, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Ludwig & Meyer Typefoundry, s, 1930; 3 (Box 2)
  - Dominante, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Johann Schweitzer-Ludwig & Meyer Typefoundry, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Dominante, Simoncini, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Dynamic, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Berthold Type Foundry, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Dynamic Medium, American Type Founders Company, 1930; 2 (Box 2)
  - Egizio, Amsterdam Continental, undated; 4 (Box 2)
  - Egmont, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Typefoundry Amsterdam, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Egmont, Intertype, S.H. de Roos, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Egmont, Lettergieterij Amsterdam, S.H. de Roos, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Egyptian, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Typefoundry Amsterdam, undated; 4 (Box 2)
  - Egyptian Expanded, American Wood Type Mfg. Co. (distributor), Stephenson Blake, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Elan, International Typeface Corp., 1985; 1 (Box 2)
  - Elegant Sans, D. Stempel AG, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Elizabeth, Bauer Alphabets, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Empire, American Type Founders, 1937; 1 (Box 2)
  - Eras, International Typeface Corp., 1976; 4 (Box 2)
  - Erasmus Initials, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Typefoundry Amsterdam, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Erbar Grotesk, Continental Typefounders (distributor), Ludwig & Meyer, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Esprit, International Typeface Corp., 1985; 1 (Box 2)
  - Eurostile, Amsterdam Continental, Aldo Novarese, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Eve, Continental Typefounders Assoc., 1933; 1 (Box 2)
  - Eve, Klingspor Typefounders, Rudolph Koch, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Excelsior, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Typefoundry Amsterdam, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Excelsior Script, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Typefoundry Amsterdam, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Fairfield, Mergenthaler Linotype, Rudolph Ruzicka, 1940; 2 (Box 2)
  - Fairfield Medium, Mergenthaler Linotype, Rudolph Ruzicka, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Falcon, Mergenthaler Linotype, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Fence, International Typeface Corp., 1980; 2 (Box 2)
  - Flex, Continental Typefounders, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Folio Family, Bauer Alphabets, 1960; 3+ items (Box 2)
  - Forte, Monotype Corporation Ltd., Carl Reissberger, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Fortune/Fortuna, Bauer Alphabets, K.F. Bauer and Walter Baum, 1956; 1 (Box 2)
  - Fontana, Monotype Corporation, Hans Mardersteig, 1936; 1 (Box 2)
  - Fontanesi, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Nebiolo Type Foundry, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Francesca Ronde, Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - Franklin Gothic, International Typeface Corp., 1980; 1 (Box 2)
  - Franklin Oldstyle, Mergenthaler Linotype, Alexander Phemister, 1927; 1 (Box 2)
  - Friz Quadrata, International Typeface Corp., Ernst Fritz, 1974; 5 (Box 2)
  - Frutiger, Eltra Corp., 1976; 1 (Box 2)
  - Futura, Bauer Type Foundry, Paul Renner, 1930; 1 (Box 2)
  - Futura, Intertype, 1939; 2 (Box 2)
  - Futura, Oscar Leventhal Composing Room (distributor), Bauer Type Foundry, undated; 3 (Box 2)
  - Galliard, Stinehour Press (distributor), Mergenthaler Linoterm, 1980; 2 (Box 2)
  - Galliard, International Typeface Corporation, 1981; 2 (Box 2)
  - Gamma, International Typeface Corporation, 1986; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Garamond, Adobe, 1989; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Garamond, American Type Founders, 1925; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Garamond, D. Stempel AG, 1930; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Garamond, International Typeface Corp., Tony Stan, 1977; 6 items (Box 2)
  - Garamond, Ludlow Typograph Co., 1930; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Garamond No. 3, Mergenthaler Linotype, T.M. Cleland, undated; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Garamond Condensed, International Typeface Corp., 1977; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Gill Sans, Eltra Corp., 1976; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Girder, Continental Typefounders Association, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Glypha, Mergenthaler/Stempel, Adrian Frutiger, 1979; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Goudy (text and Lombardic capitals), Lanston Monotype Corp., Frederic W. Goudy, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Goudy Sans, International Typeface Corporation, 1986; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Goudy Cursive, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Granjon Old Face, Linotype Machinery Ltd., 1927; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Graph, International Typeface Corp., 1975; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Grot 9, American Wood Type Mfg. Co. (distributor), Stephenson Blake, not dated, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Grotesque, Typographic Service Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Grotesque, Wescott & Thompson Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Grotesque No. 9, Lettering Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Hammer Unical, Gerb Klingspor AM, 1923; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Headline, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Ludwig & Meyer, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Hellenic Wide, Bauer Alphabets, undated; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Helvetica, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), D. Stempel AG, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Helvetica, Typographics Communication (distributor), Mergenthaler Linotype Co., undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Helvetica, Tri-Arts Press, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Hidalgo, Amsterdam Continental, Typefoundry Amsterdam, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Hidalgo, American Type Founders, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Hobo, Mergenthaler, 1977; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Horizon, Bauer Alphabets, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ideal, The Composing Room Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ideal, Intertype, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Imperial, Intertype Co., undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Impressum, Bauer Alphabets, Konrad F. Bauer and Walter Baum, undated; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Information, Amsterdam Continental (distributor), Stempel Foundry, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ionic No. 5, Mergenthaler Linotype, 1928; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Isbell, International Typeface Corporation, 1980; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Italia, International Typeface Corporation, Colin Brignall, 1977; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Italian Oldstyle, Lanston Monotype, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Janson, Lanston Monotype Machine Co., Sol Hess, 1937; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Jenson, American Type Founders, 1900; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Kabel, Continental Typefounders Assn., Rudolph Koch, 1930; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Kabel, International Typeface Corp., Rudolph Koch, 1976; 5 items (Box 2)
  - Karnak, Ludlow Typograph, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Kaufmann Script, American Type Founders, M.R. Kaufmann, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Kennerly, H.W. Caslon & Co. Ltd., 1930; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Keyboard, Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Klang, American Wood Type Mfg. Co. (distributor), Stephenson Blake, Will Carter, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Korinna, International Typeface Corp., 1977; 6 items (Box 3)
  - Largo, Amsterdam continental (distributor), Ludwig & Mayer, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Latin, Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Latin-hand lettered, Lettering Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Leawood, International Typeface Corporation, 1985; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Legend, Bauer Type Foundry, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Liberty Series, American Type Founders, m, 1928; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Libra, American Type Founders (distributor), Typefoundry Amsterdam, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Lichte Fette Grotesk, Ludwig & Mayer, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Lilith, Bauer Alphabets, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Lithos, Adobe, 1989; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Locarno, Continental Typefounders Assn., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Lubalin Graph, International Typeface Corp., Herb Lubalin, 1975; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Lucian, Bauer Alphabets, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Lucina, Ludwig & Mayer, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Lydian, American Type Founders, Warren Chappell, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Marathon, European Typefounders Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Mayer-Baruch, Jerusalem Type Foundry, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Maxime, Bauer Alphabets, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Medieval, Intertype, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Melior, Amsterdam Continental, Hermann Zapf, undated; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Melior, Typographic Service Inc., Hermann Zapf, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Memphis, Mergenthaler Linotype, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Mercury, American wood Type Mfg. Co., Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Meridien, Deberny et Pignot, undated; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Meridien, TypoGraphics Communications, Inc., 1978; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Metropolis, Continental Type Founders Assn., D. Stempel AG, 1930; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Microgramma, Amsterdam Continental, Nebiolo Type Foundry, undated; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Minion, Adobe, 1992; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Minion Cyrillic, Adobe, 1992; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Mistral, Amsterdam Continental, Roger Excoffon, undated; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Mixage, International Typeface Corporation, 1985; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Modern No. 216, International Typeface Corporation, 1982; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Mondial, European Typefounders, D. Stempel Typefoundry, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Mole Foliate, American Wood Type Mfg. Co., Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Monticello, Mergenthaler Linotype, Binny & Ronaldson, undated; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Murray Hill, American Type Founders, Emil Klumpp, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Myriad, Adobe, 1992; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Neuland, Wm. C. Popper & Co., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Neuland, Continental Typefounders, Rudolph Koch, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - News Gothic, American Type Founders, Morris Benton, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - News Gothic, Typographic Service Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Newtext, International Typeface Corporation, Ray Baker, 1975; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Nicholas Cochin, H.W. Caslon & Co., 1930; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Nicholas Cochin, American Type Founders, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Nobel, American Type Founders, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Normande, Amsterdam Continental, Berthold Type Foundry, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Normande-hand lettered, Lettering Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Normandia Outline, Amsterdam Continental, Nebiolo Type Foundry, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Novarese, International Typeface Corporation, 1979; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Old Style No. 7, Mergenthaler Linotype, 1927; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Optima, Amsterdam Continental, Hermann Zapf, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Optima, D. Stempel A.G., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Optima, Huxley House, Hermann Zapf, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Optima, Typographic Service Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Optima, John C. Meyer & Son, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Optima, Stinehour Press (distributor), Mergenthaler Linoterm, 1980; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Optima-hand lettered, Lettering Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Pabst Extra Bold Family, Mergenthaler Linotype, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Palatino Series, Amsterdam Continental, Hermann Zapf, undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Palatino, Stempel Typefounders, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Paramount, American Tyepfounders Company, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Park Avenue, American Type Founders, Robert E. Smith, undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Pascal, Amsterdam Continental, Jose Mendoza y Almeida, undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Peignot, Mergenthaler, 1977; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Perpetua, Monotype, Eltra Corp., 1976; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Penumbra, Adobe, 1995; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Pistilli, Aaron Burns & Co., John Pistilli, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Plantin, Monotype Corp., undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Playbill, Stephenson Blake, undated; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Poetica, Adobe, 1992; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Poliphilus, Monotype Corporation Ltd., undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Post-Mediaeval, Amsterdam Continental, Herbert Post, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Post Roman, Amsterdam Continental, Herbert Post, undated; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Post Title, Amsterdam Continental, Herbert Post, undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Primer, The Composing Room, Rudolph Ruzicka, undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Primer, Mergenthaler Linotype, Rudolph Ruzicka, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Primula, Typefoundry Amsterdam, Imre Reiner, undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Quorum, International Typeface Corporation, Ray Baker, 1977; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Radiant, Ludlow Typograph Company, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Raleigh Cursive, American Type Founders, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Raleigh Series, Mergenthaler, 1978; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Record Gothic, Ludlow Typograph Company, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Recta, Nebiolo Type Foundry, Aldo Novarese, undated; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Regal, Intertype, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Rhapsodie, Amsterdam Continental, Ludwig & Mayer, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Rondo, American Type Founders, Dick Dooyes, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Rondo, Amsterdam Continental, undated; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Shadow, American Type Founders, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Sabon, Stinehour Press (distributor), Mergenthaler Linoterm, 1980; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Sabon, Monotype Corporation Ltd., Jan Tschichold, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Sanvito, Adobe, 1993; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Saskia, Jan Tschichold, 1931 1933; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Scotch Series, Mergenthaler Linotype, 1922; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Serif Gothic, International Typeface Corporation, Herb Lubalin and Antonia DiSpigna, 1974; 5 items (Box 9)
  - Simoncini Life Series, Mergenthaler, 1978; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Slimbach, International Typeface Corporation, 1987; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Souvenir, International Typeface Corporation, Ed Benguiat, 1974; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Spartan, American Type Founders, not dated, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Spartan, Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Spectrum, Monotype Corporation, Jan Van Krimpen, 1954; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Standard, Amsterdam Continental, Berthold Type Foundry, undated; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Standard, John C. Meyer & Son, undated; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Stellar, Ludlow Typograph Co., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Stencil, American Type Founders, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Stradivarious, Bauer Alphabets, undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Studio, American Type Founders (distributor), Typefoundry Amsterdam, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Stymie Bold Condensed, American Type Founders, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Symbol, International Typeface Corporation, 1984; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Tea-Chest, Stephenson Blake, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Tekton, Adobe, 1993; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Throwgood, Stephenson Blake, undated; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Thorne Shaded, Stephenson Blake, Robert Thorne, undated; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Tiepolo, International Typeface Corporation, 1987; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Tiffany, International Typeface Corporation, Ed Benguiat, 1974; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Times New Roman, Advertising Agencies' Service Co., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Times Roman, The Composing Room, Stanley Morison, undated; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Times Roman, The Stinehour Press (distributor), Mergenthaler Linoterm, 1980; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Times Roman, Lettering Inc., undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Times Roman, Mergenthaler Linotype, Stanley Morison, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Times Roman, John C. Meyer & Son, undated; 1 item (Box 9)